[music]
[Instructor] We've got a "for() loop"
set up, so now when we press Play,
you can see the 3 different
enemies spawning around.
If we're going to increase the number
of enemies that spawn in our game,
we'll actually need
to be able to pass information
to our method using Parameters.
In our SpawnManager Script,
we have our "SpawnEnemyWave()" method.
Now, how do we actually
add Parameters to our method,
so that way we can tell
it numbers of enemies
that we want to spawn over time?
In fact, it's fairly easy.
What we can do is,
we can type in "int...
enemiesToSpawn,"
and now this creates
an "enemiesToSpawn" variable
that we can then use
throughout our code.
So, instead of ending
our for() loop when "i < 3,"
we can end our for() loop
when "i < enemiesToSpawn."
We've been using
Parameters the entire time
with a lot of our methods,
to be able to pass in information
like enemyPrefab,
or the rotation,
and in this case,
we can use something
as simple as an integer variable
to pass in the number of enemies
that we want to spawn,
every time we call this method.
One thing you'll notice
is our SpawnEnemyWave() method
at our Start() method is pretty angry
with us right now,
because it actually needs
a number to start with.
So, we can press 3,
and now when we play our game,
we should just see 3 enemies
spawn once again.
You can see that adding Parameters
to our methods can be
a fairly easy process.
Then, if we wanted to, we could just
use something as simple as a comma,
and state another random
thing to be able to...
use a second variable. And, we can add
in as many Parameters as we want,
but it's best to keep the Parameters
to as minimum as possible
so that way you're not using
too many things,
if you don't need to.
One other point to mention here,
just to notice,
you can see
that here in our SpawnEnemyWave(),
we have a "void" method,
and then in our GenerateSpawnPosition(),
we have a "Vector3".
So, you can see here the difference
in when you would really use
a "void" method,
versus a method that returns something.
Where with our GenerateSpawnPosition(),
we want it to give us information
on a random position
that we want to generate,
versus our SpawnEnemyWave()
method is just doing something.
In this case,
doing the task
of creating different
numbers of enemies,
based on how many enemies we want.
In this case too, we need
a Parameter
to tell SpawnEnemyWave()
how many enemies we want to spawn,
but, in our GenerateSpawnPosition(),
we don't need any Parameters
because it's already doing
all the calculations
inside of the method.
So, what you're going to do is,
in your SpawnEnemyWave() method,
you're going to add a Parameter,
which is an int of the number
of enemiesToSpawn.
You're going to replace the 3
in i < 3 of your for() loop,
with the enemiesToSpawn variable,
and then in your "Start()" method,
just make sure that in SpawnEnemyWave(),
you add an integer in there to tell
the method how many enemies
you want to spawn. Now it's your turn.
[music]